<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Spells</name>
		<description>Spells from Omeria</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ShadowLinks/omeria-elements/main/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Airstrike" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_AIRSTRIKE">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Elementalist, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a dramatic burst of air that appears as a 60-foot-high cylinder that’s 15 feet in diameter centered on the point you choose. Each creature in the area must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed saving throw, the target is slammed into the ground; it takes 5d6 bludgeoning damage plus an additional 1d6 damage for every 10 feet it fell and it is prone. On a successful saving throw, the target takes half as much damage and isn’t knocked prone.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning, prone</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Amraam's Explosive Decompression" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_AMRAAMS_EXPLOSIVE_DECOMPRESSION">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a severe imbalance of positive and negative energy which then suddenly inverts. Choose a creature within range. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 6d12 force damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much damage on a successful one. If the spell reduces the target to 0 hit points, the target explosively decompresses and dies. Additionally, each target within 10 feet of the exploding target must make a Dexterity saving throw or take 3d12 force damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d12 for each slot above 4th level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">force</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a gem worth at least 10 gp</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Blade" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_BLADE">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You target one creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 2d10 fire damage and the target catches fire. Until a creature, including the target, uses its action to douse the flames, the target automatically takes 1d10 fire damage at the start of each of its turns.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the initial damage increases by 1d10 for each slot above 3rd level. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">cloth dipped in lantern oil</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Crush" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_CRUSH">
        <supports>Druid, Elementalist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure a boulder before you which you then launch in a line that’s 30 feet long and 5 feet wide. The creature closest to you in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed saving throw, the target takes 2d10 bludgeoning damage and the spell ends. On a successful saving throw, the creature takes no damage and the boulder continues on to the next creature in the line. The second creature must make a similar saving throw as the first creature with similar consequences. This continues until the boulder moves the full 30 feet or a target fails its saving throw, whichever happens first. You can use your action on subsequent turns to conjure a new boulder and launch it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the length of the line increases by 10 feet for each slot level above 1st. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (30-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">A small piece of crystal</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Drown" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_DROWN">
        <supports>Druid, Elementalist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You target one creature of your choice that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or it begins to drown. While drowning, the target takes 4d8 necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns. The target can repeat its saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself with a success.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a drop of soiled water</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Fist" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_EARTH_FIST">
        <supports>Druid, Elementalist, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The ground at a point within range sprouts an earthen arm which remains for the duration.</p>
            <p class="indent">The arm is an object that has AC 17 and hit points equal to 3 x your caster level. If it drops to 0 hit points, the spell ends. It has a Strength of 20 (+5) and a Dexterity of 9 (-1). The arm doesn’t fill its space.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you cast the spell and as a bonus action on your subsequent turns, you can cause one of the following effects with it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Move.</em></strong> The arm moves up to 20 feet to a space that you can see within 60 feet of you and sprouts out of the ground there. It does not provoke attacks of opportunity when it moves. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Slam.</em></strong> The arm makes a melee spell attack against a target within 5 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 bludgeoning damage. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Grab.</em></strong> The arm attempts to grapple a Medium or smaller creature within 5 feet of it. You use the arm’s Strength score to resolve the grapple. While the hand is grappling the target, you can use a bonus action to have the hand crush it. When you do so, the target takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage from the slam option increases by 1d6, and the damage from the grab option increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 3rd. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">five small pieces of crystal</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Earth Shield" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_EARTH_SHIELD">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You conjure an earthen shield which forms around your arm. For the duration, you gain 15 temporary hit points, including against the triggering attack.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you gain an additional 10 temporary hit points for each slot level above 1st. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">Temporary Hit Points</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when you are hit by an attack or targeted by the magic missile spell</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">1 round</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Environmental Preservation" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_ENVIRONMENTAL_PRESERVATION">
        <supports>Druid, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You make an area within range magically secure from harmful weather, destructive forces, and other effects. The area is a cube that can be 100 feet on each side. The spell lasts for the duration or until you use an action to dismiss it.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you cast the spell, you decide what sort of security the spell provides, choosing any or all of the following properties.</p>
            <ul>
                <li> The creatures and plants within the area are protected against extreme unnatural shifts in weather or climate. For example, an arctic environment would become immune to the effects of extreme heat, or a tropical forest would become immune to the effects of extreme cold.</li>
                <li>The barrier of the warded area appears blurry or foggy, preventing vision (including darkvision) through it.</li>
                <li>Until the spell ends, any creature inside the warded area that tries to damage or harm the nonmagical plants or beasts inside the warded area must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed saving throw, the creature cannot harm the area for 24 hours.</li>
                <li> Plant creatures and beasts inside the warded area have advantage on saving throws.</li>
                <li>The area comes under the protection of a fey creature called nature’s defender. It manifests within the warded area in an unoccupied space that you can see. The creature remains until it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends. The creature is friendly toward you and your companions, but it is not controlled by you. Its only purpose is to protect the warded area.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">Casting this spell on the same spot every day for 1 year makes this effect permanent.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, you can increase the size of the cube by 100 feet for each slot level beyond 5th. Thus you could protect a cube that can be up to 200 feet on one side by using a spell slot of 6th level. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">range mile</set>
            <set name="duration">24 hours</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">soil from the target location, a feather, a candle, and a vial containing water from a nearby source</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Fiendform" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_FIENDFORM">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell temporarily turns a willing creature into a fiend. Until the spell ends, the creature’s type becomes fiend. Until the spell ends, the target gains the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Resistance to cold, fire, and lightning damage.</li>
                <li>Darkvision out to 120 feet.</li>
                <li>Telepathy out to 60 feet.</li>
                <li>Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</li>
            </ul>
            <p class="indent">When the spell ends, the target’s mind is damaged by the spell’s effects. The target must succeed on a DC 10 Wisdom saving throw, or gain one form of long-term madness.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a charred piece of cloth</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Four Horsemen" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_FOUR_HORSEMEN">
        <supports>Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You call forth the spirits of four powerful warriors mounted on spectral horses. The horsemen manifest in unoccupied spaces that you can see within range. These incorporeal creatures each use the spectral horseman stat block. A horseman disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each horseman is an ally to you and your companions. In combat, the horsemen share your initiative count, but take their turn immediately after yours. They obey your verbal commands (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any, they take the Dodge action and use their move to avoid danger.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">summon</set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Inferno" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_INFERNO">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Columns of flame erupt in up to ten unoccupied spaces of your choice within range and last for the duration. The fire fills its space and rises 20 feet into the air. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the flames must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 6d10 fire damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action on each of your turns for the duration, you can move one of the columns up to 10 feet to another unoccupied space that you can see within range.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">5</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a small piece of phosphorus</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Lights Out" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_LIGHTS_OUT">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You target a point that you can see within range. All nonmagical light sources in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on that spot, such as candles, lanterns, and torches, are immediately extinguished. Any magical light source created by a spell of 1st level or lower is also extinguished.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Metal Militia" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_METAL_MILITIA">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric</supports>
        <description>
            <p>This spell allows you to protect up to six creatures that you can see within range. Until the spell ends, all of the targets’ skin hardens into steel. Each target’s armor class can’t be less than 19, regardless of the armor it is wearing.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">8</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a steel plate valued at 500 gp or more which is consumed by the spell</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Motorbreath" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_MOTORBREATH">
        <supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain incredible speed and reaction times for the duration of the spell, which grants you the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>When you cast this spell, and then as a bonus action on each of your turns until the spell ends, you can take the Dash action.</li>
                <li>Moving out of a creature’s space does not provoke attacks of opportunity.</li>
                <li>Your movement speed increases by 15 feet.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 10 minutes</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Papa Het's Remorseless Touch" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_PAPA_HETS_REMORSELESS_TOUCH">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You imbue one willing creature that you can see within range with the spirit of war. For the duration, once per turn, when the target deals damage to another creature with an attack, it regains hit points equal to half the damage dealt.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">heal</set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a drop of blood</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Phantom Lord" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_PHANTOM_LORD">
        <supports>Bard, Cleric, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>For the spell’s duration, you can use your bonus action to target one undead creature that you can see within range. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for the duration, until it takes damage from you, or until it is 60 feet or further from you. This spell counts as an effect that turns undead for the purposes of Turn Immunity and Resistance.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">incense</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Riptide" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_RIPTIDE">
        <supports>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You create a blast of water forming a line 100 feet long and 15 feet wide which blasts out from you in a direction of your choice. Each creature in the line must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 4d10 bludgeoning damage, is pushed back 15 feet and knocked prone. On a successful saving throw, a target takes half as much damage and is not pushed back or knocked prone.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 2d10 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
            <set name="level">4</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">Self (100-foot line)</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">tip of a manta ray's tail</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Seek and Destroy" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_SEEK_AND_DESTORY">
        <supports>Bard, Paladin, Ranger, Warlock</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You choose a creature you can see within range and mystically mark it as your quarry. Until the spell ends, you have advantage on weapon attacks made against that creature. If the target drops to 0 hit points before this spell ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to mark a new creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Divination</set>
            <set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
            <set name="range">90 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Concentration up to 1 hour</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">true</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tirden's Illusory Distraction" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_TIRDENS_ILLUSORY_DISTRACTION">
        <supports>Bard, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You throw a Tiny object such as a rock or a bit of wood at a point that you can see within range. When the object lands, it creates a distracting series of sounds. Each creature within range of the object that can hear the sounds must make a Wisdom saving throw. Any creature that can’t be charmed succeeds on this saving throw automatically, and if you or your companions are fighting a creature, it has advantage on the save. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to perceive anything else until the spell ends or until the target can no longer hear the sounds. Physical interaction with the object reveals the sounds to be an illusion, unless the item could actually produce the sounds (for example, the small object might be a bell that creates a ringing sound). A creature that uses its action to examine the object can determine that the sounds are an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the sounds become faint to the creature, and the creature is no longer affected by the illusion.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">3</set>
            <set name="school">Illusion</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">1 minute</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a Tiny object such as a rock or bit of wood which is thrown</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tooth Decay" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_TOOTH_DECAY">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You target one creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or it takes 1 necrotic damage and its teeth fall out. Until the creature receives magical healing, it has disadvantage on all Charisma checks that require it to interact with a creature that can see or hear it, as well as on attacks that rely on its bite. A creature that does not have or need teeth is immune to this spell’s effects.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
            <set name="level">2</set>
            <set name="school">Necromancy  </set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">60 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">a tooth</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Whiplash" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_WHIPLASH">
        <supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You target one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or take 1d8 thunder damage and be pushed back 5 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">The spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">thunder</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">120 feet</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>

<!-- 

    <element name="Spellname" type="Spell" source="Omeria" id="ID_DMDAVE_OMERIA_SPELL_SPELLNAME">
        <supports>supports</supports>
        <description>
            <p></p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords"></set>
            <set name="level">level</set>
            <set name="school">Evocation</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="range">range</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent">component</set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    -->